i live in the pacific northwest now a
lot of people where i live think i
should have a deeper
more redneck southern accent because of
where i'm from which
you're nodding that hurts my feelings
that's fine uh
it's okay i want to let you all know in
the fine city of provo
uh that not all of us sound like extras
from the movie deliverance all right
and not every child born in the south is
born with like one side of their
overalls undone plugging on a banjo
[Laughter]
they're just like give me the sweet tea
give me sweet tea mama
that's not how it works no most children
in the south eventually lose their
southern accent so
you know like for me it happened right
around the time i learned to read
i'm not being a jerk you guys just don't
know what it's like to be a young
southern man reading a book and be like
all right
if that's how that's spelled i've been
saying it wrong that is
[Laughter]
[Applause]
is that a new letter what is that it's
like a t but there's a little thing at
the bottom of it
anyway who knew there were more than 23
letters
people people in hollywood have two
southern accents they do
they do redneck inbred horrible southern
which is basically what i've been doing
this entire time
and then the other one is what i call
plantation owner southern and even if
you don't thank you
even if you don't know she's a little
ahead she'll fill you guys in when you
catch
up she'll have a powerpoint it'll be
some spark notes it'll be good
[Laughter]
plantation owner southern even if you
haven't heard it you've heard it
it just goes like oh hello there i'm not
one of those
dumb southerners you've heard all about
i drink mojitos down by the beach and
read from leather-bound books that i
don't own or whatever
i hate that accent i hate it because i
know when i hear that accident in a
movie
i'm about to hear some ignorant stuff go
down
because that's somebody be like oh he's
he's a rich southerner give him that
accent kevin spacey does in all his
movies
what i hate about that accent is
hollywood has decided that that is a
fancy accent but i'ma let you guys know
that that
is not how accents work if you have an
accent you just have it you can't just
give it to rich people
you don't like screwing a monocle like i
can't stop talking like this now
i guess it just comes with the monocle
who knew it did not say on the box when
i did it that it was gonna do this
yeah you'll be walking downtown in like
alabama
you're gonna see some guy in front of a
gas station like excuse me sir
can i borrow a dollar to go in here and
buy some flamin hot cheetos
yeah i don't mean to be rude i gotta
take this call for my brother in the
penitentiary
in the meantime you can talk to my wife
we met down at the what you call a
gathering of the juggalos
she said a job interview like good sir i
would love to accept this position at
ladies footlocker but
i definitely cannot pass a drug test
will that or will that not be a deal
breaker
well all right i will see myself out
then
the best thing about southern accents if
you look at the history
of the southern accent there was a time
when the southeastern part of the united
states
was colonized by the british those are
our ancestors
how did we go from the fanciest accent
on earth
to the living banjo of an accent
that we have today how did we go from
duke of edmonton to dukes of hazzard i
want to know
i need to know if i know anything
about the proud southern people i bet we
did it intentionally
yeah out of spite for the british
we just heard we won the revolutionary
war we had our guns in the air like boom
boom boom we're never talking like them
losers again one of the generals is like
yeah come here come here your name's
cletus now come here
fill all our tea with sugar cletus
they'll write us letters they'll be like
that's not tea we'll be like it's sweet
tea and it's all we drink now
you write them a letter take this down
cletus you tell them i said why don't
they go back to where we came from
uh that is either the smartest dumb joke
you're ever gonna hear
or the dumbest smart joke either way by
the end of it it's only ever for about a
fourth of you guys
and people go why do you keep telling it
and i go because i get to yell a lot
if you look it up accents typically form
within the first six months you're on
earth based on the people talking around
you
and when i read that fact i started
cackling with laughter
because you know somebody out there has
faked a sweet
exotic accent for half a year and
ended up with a cool kid with an awesome
accent
somebody out there has done that i'm not
the smartest person i know and i thought
of it somebody's done that
i couldn't do it for two reasons first
one perhaps maybe the biggest one
i don't have a kid and i feel like
i wouldn't be able to get one for six
months enough to test this
and i feel like when they get him back
my excuse of like i just tried to make
him sound cool why are you arresting me
or whatever
i don't think that's gonna fly in a
court of law
[Laughter]
the other one is that i am uh very
horrible at any non-southern accent
and i really don't want to mess up my
kid right i don't want my kid to come up
to me at the age of 10
finally working up the nerve to ask his
old man that question that's always been
on his mind you know
he comes tugging at my shirt sleeve
father
father why do i talk like this
nobody else in the world take a look at
this for me father
i don't even know what i would say to
him in that moment
i probably try to be honest with him and
say something like uh
i figured you were going to ask me
eventually but
anyway daddy was going for italian
[Laughter]
i don't really know anybody from italy
though so i kind of just went with mario
[Applause]
local man robs wendy's with alligator
for the alligator boys now
[Music]
mom